本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：joanna    校对：小路     时间轴：虫不知
特效：Will     校对：冰卡      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第一集
这啥玩意儿  怎么是蓝的
What is this? It's blue.
我们改了下化学制程  不过纯度还是一样的
We used a different chemical process,but it is every bit as pure.
别看它是蓝的  吸着一样赞
May be blue, but it's the bomb.
赞  赞  太赞了
Tight, tight, tight... Yeah.
什么蓝的黄的...
Blue, yellow, pink...
管它什么颜色  就要这样的货色
Whatever man.Just keep bringing me that.
你们好好干  大家一起挣大钱
You're all right. We're gonna make a lot of money together.
给我记住你们在给谁干活
Just remember who you're working for.
你说什么
What did you say?
我就告诉他们  该明白他们在替你干活
I'm just saying, they gotta know that they're working for you.
你以为他们不明白吗
Like they don't already know that?
你是说他们很蠢是吧
Are you saying that they're stupid?
没有  我就说说而已
No, I'm just saying.
所以你不是在说他们蠢
Oh yeah, so you're not saying that they're stupid?
那我就不明白了  你是在说我蠢吗
So, I don't understand.Are you saying that I'm stupid?
是吗
Is that it?
是不是这个意思
Is that what you're doing?
屠库
Tuco.
我们大家都...
Why don't we all just...
放松一下
Relax?
海森堡说了  放松一下
Heisenberg says, "relax."
我很放松  我很放松
I'm relaxed. I'm relaxed.
我非常放松
I'm relaxed...
该死的  看看这个  看看
Damn, man!Look at that! Look!
真他妈混蛋
Yeah. That's messed up.
行了  海森堡
Okay, Heisenberg!
下周见
Next week.
考虑到通货膨胀
Adjusting for inflation...
好的州立大学  考虑到通货膨胀影响
Good state college,adjusting for inflation,
算它4万5千一年  两个孩子  上四年大学
Say $45,000 a year.Two kids, four years of college,
那就是36万
$360,000.
房贷还有10万7没还
Remaing mortgage on the home,107 thousand.
加上房贷利息3万  一共是13万7
Home equity line, 30 thousand.That's 137 thousand.
生活费
Cost of living,
吃的  穿的  水电煤气什么的
food, clothing, utilities,
算它每月两千
Say two grand a month,
其实还可以少算点的
And that should put a dent in it,anyway.
一年就是2万4
24K a year.
按十年来算
Provide for say,10 years.
就是24万  加上36万  再加13万7
That's $240,000.Plus 360, plus 1, 3, 7...
73万7
737.
我一共需要73万7
$737,000.That is what I need.
就是这个数
That's what I need.
你跟我每周各净赚7万
You and I both clear about 70 grand a week,
那就只要再干10个半礼拜  算它11
That's only 10 and a half More weeks.Call it 11...
再干11单买卖  只在公共场所交易
11 more drug deals, and always in a public place from now on.
可行的  绝对可行的
It's do-able.Definitely do-able.
海森堡
Heisenberg!
到底怎么了  他怎么回事
What the hell?What's wrong with him?
你他妈怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
这么不经揍是吧  妈的
You can't take an ass-beating,bitch?
-情况不妙  屠库  -闭嘴
- Damn, Tuco... - Shut up.
脉搏停掉了
There's no pulse.
-干点什么啊  -我能干什么啊
- Do something.- Do something?
该叫救护车把他送医急救
He needs an ambulance.He needs a hospital.
干点什么  你不是很聪明的吗
Do something!You're smart, right?
给他做  做那个
Do that... Do that thing!
没有  没什么用
No, there's... There's nothing.
-给他人工呼吸  -早就不推荐用这招了
- Breathe into his mouth... - No, they don't teach that anymore.
-没有用的  -你  过来
- It doesn't work. - You, come here!
给他做人工呼吸
Breathe into his mouth!
别动
No
把他处理掉
Get rid of him.
老大  我们不能这么对他
We can't do him like that, man.
不能像处理掉个秃鹰或老鼠什么的
Buzzards and rats and all that.
我是说  我们可是基督教徒  不能这么干的
I'm just saying, you know?It's not very Christian.
你这是在违抗命令吗
It sounds like arguing.
怪诞  快点
Gonzo, hurry up!
这么急着走干嘛
What's the big hurry?
我只是以为  这儿没我们什么事了
I just think we're done here.
好吧  你们完事儿了
Well...you're done.
我在后边呢
Hey, I'm back here!
有人吗
Hello?
沃尔特  听到我讲话了吗
Walt...Didn't you hear me?
沃尔特
Walt...
淡定
Hey, yourself.
我叫你的时候你不能答应一声吗
What, you can't answer when I'm calling you?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
很好
Great.
新帽子
New hat?
我在艾伯森食品店买了点烤鸡
I got some grilled chicken at Albertson's.
要帮你热一下吗
You want me to heat some up for you?
你去哪了
Where've you been?
你看看  我脸上还涂着这玩意儿
Do you know what,I've got all this crap on my face.
让我先洗掉吧  好吗
Let me clean up first, okay?
小沃尔特随时会回来  所以
You know, Walter Junior's gonna be home any minute, so...
好吧  好  够了
Ok just...enough.
等一下
Hold up.
停下
Stop it.
Stop it!
我知道你心里害怕
I know you're scared,
你愤怒又沮丧  我也知道老天对你不公
And you're angry,and you're frustrated.And I know none of this is fair.
但你不能拿我出气
But you cannot take it out on me.
我回来了
Hey, I'm home!
我们死定了
We are dead.
死定了
Dead, man!
挂了  完了  不管你TM怎么说
Muerto! Ormuerte! However the hell you...
-别疑神疑鬼的  -我疑神疑鬼
- This is conjecture. - This is conjecture?
是的  瞎猜是没有用的
Yes. And conjecture isn't helping.
我在瞎猜吗  好吧
My conjecture isn't helping. Fine.
给我听着  首先
Facts then. Fact A:
我的电话  昨晚响了七八次
My phone rang, like, eight times last night.
每次都不说话  接起来就挂了
Dead air, hang ups every time.
第二
Second fact:
凌晨三点  我看到他那辆黑色卡迪拉克
3 in the morning, I saw that black Caddy
在这附近转悠  没打灯
Of his cruising my neighborhood.No headlights.
如果他真想杀我们
If he wanted to kill us,
在废车场那会早就动手了
He would've done it at the junkyard.
你那算什么  瞎猜
What is that? Conjecture?
你有啥根据  你是觉得他脑筋正常
Are you basing that on that he's got a normal,
还是怎么的
healthy brain or something?
没看到他打死个人  一点不当回事吗
Did you not see him beat a dude to death for, like, nothing?
还有  还有他死瞪着我们说
And that way... that way he just kept staring at us,saying,
你们完事儿了
"You're done."
什么叫你们完事儿了
"You're done"?
你想知道吗  我来告诉你那什么意思
You wanna know what that means?I will tell you what that means.
那就是说你们玩完了
That means exactly how it sounds, yo!
这下好了  我们是目击证人  需要好好收拾
All right. We are witnesses.We are loose ends.
现在  屠库正想着  是啊
Right now, Tuco's thinking,"Yeah, hey,
他们的货做得不错  但他们可信吗
"they cook good meth,but can I trust them?"
当他觉得咱不可信的时候他会怎么着
What happens when he decides no?
不是他死就是我们亡  明白吗  你自己选吧
It's him or us! You understand?It is him or us!
你想怎么做
How would you do it?
-什么意思  -你的具体计划
- What do you mean? - Specifically,
你想怎么做  一步一步说
How would you do it? Step by step.
好吧
All right.
我们可以这样...
Say we...
再安排一次交易
Set up one last sale, this is providing
只要他不在此之前废了我们
He doesn't decide to waste us before then.
每次我们带了新货  他总会
Every time we bring in a new batch,he always...
先验货对吧  所以
Tests the product, right? So,
趁他低头  深吸一口的时候  砰  砰  砰
As his head is down...you know, just giving it a snort...
砰  砰  砰  三枪搞定吗
So three shots?
-三枪  我不知道  或者两枪  -到底两枪还是三枪
- Three shots, or, I don't know, two.- But is it two, or is it three?
-也许两枪就够了  -两枪  打胸口
- Two would probably work, I guess. - Two shots in the chest?
-还是打脸  -拜托
- Or in the face? - Come on...
我只想搞清楚到底怎么才行
I'm just trying to understand how this works.
好吧  这个晚点再议  不过在此之前
All right. We'll providing in that.But by now,
那个大块头  怪诞  他会对付你  是吧
The big guy, Gonzo... he's probably coming at you, right?
然后你瞄准他  对他要开几枪
So you turn toward him...How many shots for him?
他块头很大  是吧  对他得开几枪才行呢
He's a big guy, right?How many shots does that take?
-我不知道  三枪吧  -好的  三枪
- I don't know. Three shots. - Okay, three shots.
屠库和怪诞  这两个干掉了  那么  还有别人吗
Tuco and Gonzo. Two men down.Now, is there anyone else there?
我是说  屠库通常都会带上其他人  是吧
I mean, Tuco is usually with someone else, right?
可能会带好几个  他的同伙  手下
Maybe even a couple of guys.His dealers, his posse.
好吧
All right.
这个我们也暂且不论
So we'll put a pin in that one, too.
现在  你一共开了几枪了
Now, at this point,how many shots have been fired?
子弹还有剩吗  你那枪能装几颗子弹
You've gotta be running low.How many bullets does that gun take?
你连个弹匣都打不开
How can you suggest
还想用这去杀人
That we kill a man and you can't even open the gun?
没那么容易  是吧
It's not that easy, is it?
拜托  沃尔特  你就杀过
Hey, man, Walt, you did it.
呼叫斯凯勒
Call Skyler.
你好  这里是沃尔特  斯凯勒  小沃尔特的家
Hey, there. You've reached Walt,Skyler, and Walter Junior.
现在没法接听您的电话  有事请留言
We can't come to the phone right now,so please leave us a message.
你们还真是早起的鸟儿啊  一早就出去了
Well, aren't you early bird,up and out already.
我和大笨猪今晚想去试试
The big lug and I are gonna go try
新墨西哥大学那儿新开的餐馆
That new restaurant over by UNM tonight.
如果想"嗨皮"就一起吧
So let me know if you guys wanna hang.
听听我说的  "嗨皮"
Listen to me. "Hang."
小沃尔特肯定会很骄傲
Walt Junior would be proud.
我连这都知道
I know the lingo.
还挺时髦的
I'm still hip.
那是家中餐馆
It's Chinese... the restaurant.
不知道为什么  我就是喜欢中餐
I don't know.I just feel like Chinese.
你觉得中国人
Do you think that people in China
也会喜欢西餐吗
Ever just feel like American?
我是说  他们会不会
You know, and they go out
叫上点外卖
And get little take-out boxes
比如土豆泥烤肉饼什么的
With mashed potatoes and meat loaf,
他们会不会学着用小刀小叉
And try and figure out how to use the little knives and forks?
我很好奇会不会有这样的事
I wonder if that ever happens.
好吧  不废话了  给我回电话
All right. I'll let you go.So call me.
斯凯勒没接电话吗
Skyler didn't pick up?
她肯定不在家
Obviously she's not home.
你刚说什么中餐馆来着
What was that about Chinese?
就新开的那家  想今晚去吃
Dinner tonight.That new place.
-他们营业到几点  -我不知道
- How late they serve? - I don't know.
8点你得去见戴夫
You got Dave at 8.
没约今晚啊
Not tonight.
-是今晚  记得吗  -不  约的周四
- Yeah, you do. Remember? - No, that's Thursday.
肯定是周四
I'm pretty sure that's Thursday.
还记得最后他们怎么为你改期了吗
Remember how, at the last minute,they changed it around for you?
不去的话会罚款的
They were gonna charge us a penalty.
宝贝  只剩下六次治疗了
Look, baby,you only got six more sessions.
我会去的  汉克  我说到做到
And I'm doing them, Hank. I said I would do them, and I'm doing them.
只是你要是约错了时间  那我就没办法了
I can't help it if you got your days of the week wrong.
小心
Look out!
对不起  施拉德先生
Sorry, Mr. Schrader!
我只是觉得
Look, it's... You know, it's just...
我觉得戴夫真的对你很有帮助
I think Dave is...really helping you.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
她有点
She's...
我要打电话
Where's my phone call?
沙地上撂倒两个  树林里再撂倒一双
Hits two in the sand,two in the forest.
-然后他说  再来4个凑凑数  -戈麦斯
- And then he says, "Give me a four." - Gomez.
有什么新线索没有
What do you got for me?
拿进来  动作要快
Come on. Chop-chop.
这一大早的  催命鬼似的
Good morning to you, too.
本地警方送过来的  大概8到10天前的
APD sent this over.This was about eight or ten days ago.
-知道西南面那家苯胺厂吧  -离这25公里那家吗  知道
- You know Southwest Aniline, right? - Yeah, off the 25?
-那地方老有股脚臭味儿  -看看他们  仔细看
- Whole place smells like feet. - This is them. Check this out.
-该死的  这是什么  -铝热剂
- Holy shit. What was that? - Thermite.
他们是这么说的
So they tell me.
燃烧起来大约有5000度
Burns about 5,000 degrees.
詹姆士·邦德经常会用到这招
Kind of stuff you see on a James Bond movie.
不错嘛
Nice!
这两个家伙挺懂行的嘛
Guys who know their trade.
等等  我收回刚才的话
Wait. I take that back.
他们就没想过顺手偷个手推车吗
What, they didn't think about stealing a hand truck?
可以推着走的  笨蛋  那是个桶
Try rolling it, morons!It's a barrel.
可以用滚的  老天
It rolls. Jesus.
-他们偷了什么  -30加仑甲胺[约合113多公升]
- So what'd they get? - Methylamine, 30 gallons.
苯基丙酮制毒吗
P2P?
他们在用老式的学院派方式制毒
They're cooking old-school biker meth.
到底谁TM还在用这办法
Who the hell still does that?
我知道的老家伙们死的死抓的抓
All the old-timers I know are either dead or in prison.
最近原料短缺
Pseudo's in short supply,
所以这俩家伙想改进配方
So these two make do by changing up the formula.
知道这个还有铝热剂
That and the thermite...
不得不承认他们挺懂行的
I'd say these two know their chemistry.
但说到做贼的水平
But ranking them as burglars?
三脚猫都不算  连特奥会都轮不上他们
Shit! I wouldn't trust these two to break into the Special Olympics.
空有理论知识  没有实战经验
They got book learnin' but no street skills.
也许他们就是学生
Maybe they're college kids...
化学系的  想得个高分
Chem students trying to make a big score.
我跟你说  整整30加仑的甲胺
I tell you,30 gallons of Precursor...
这分数高的  他们也不怕被人盯上
That big a score, they're gonna wind up stepping on some toes.
要我说
Tell you what,
他们最好祈祷赶紧让我们逮着
They better pray it's us who catches up to them
别给那帮墨西哥佬盯上咯
And not those boys from Juarez.
你女儿迫不及待想出来呢
Your daughter wants out.
你好
Hey, there.
这里是沃尔特  斯凯勒  小沃尔特的家
You've reached Walt, Skyler,and Walter Junior.
现在没法接听您的电话
We can't come to the phone right now,
有事请留言
So please leave us a message.
是我
Hey, it's me.
我想这次该早点打给你
I thought I'd try you earlier this time,
趁你们还没出去开始新一天的时候
Before you go out and, you know,face the day.
我知道
I'm realizing now
你现在接电话肯定要慢好多了
It probably takes you a little longer to get to the phone,
毕竟挺着个大肚子嘛...
Owing to the extra baby weight...
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
沃尔特  你整个晚上都站在那吗
Walt, did you spend the entire night out here?
没有  不是一整晚
No, no.Well, not all of it.
我确实觉得  胃有点痛
Oh, yeah. I did have a touch of...my stomach, you know?
肯定会翻来覆去睡不着  我只是不想吵醒你
I knew I was gonna be up and down,so I just didn't want to wake you.
他怎么会知道我住哪的
How would he know where I live?
-你确定那是屠库  -不是他还能是谁
- You're sure it was Tuco? - Who else could it be?
你告诉过他我的名字住址什么的吗
Did you ever tell him my name,where I live or anything...
那怪诞呢  死掉的那个呢
What about Gonzo, or the dead one?
-你跟他们说过我什么吗  -一个字都没说过
- Did you tell them anything about me? - I didn't say jack!
屠库肯定是想探探你的底
Tuco must've put out,like, you know, feelers.
他自有他的路子和办法
He's got his ways and means, yo.
他有人脉的好吧  他正步步紧逼
Sources, all right? He's closing in.
他要是发现我小舅子是缉毒署的  那怎么办
And what happens when he finds out that my brother-in-law is a DEA agent?
天哪  那怎么办
Oh, God. What happens then?
听着  这里有5颗子弹
Look, it's got five bullets.
我总算搞清楚了怎么
I finally figured out how to...
总之  我有数了
Look, I just finally...I figured it out.
假设我们再去搞把枪给你
Say we get a second gun,right, for you.
我们的胜算不是加倍了吗
I mean, don't we, like,double our chances?
我是说  从数量上来看
I mean, mathematically.
我有个更好的主意
I've got a better idea.
谢天谢地
Thank God!
是什么  怀特先生  快说快说
All right.What is it, Mr. White?Lay it on me.
豆子
Beans.
Beans?
这是蓖麻豆
They're castor beans.
这是用来干什么吃的
So what are we gonna do with them?
你以为这是《杰克与魔豆》的故事 是吗
Are we just gonna grow a magic beanstalk, huh?
顺着豆茎往上爬就能逃出生天
Climb it and escape?
我们要用这提炼出蓖麻毒素
We are going to process them into ricin.
棺臃?
Rice and beans?
蓖麻毒素
Ricin.
是种剧毒物质
It's an extremely effective poison.
所需剂量很小
It's toxic in small doses.
尸检的时候也很容易被忽略掉
Also fairly easy to overlook during an autopsy.
-好吧  这么说  -别碰它们
- All right.So... - Don't touch them.
等等  说真的  你真的能从豆子里提炼出毒来
Wait. Seriously,you can get poison from beans?
上个世纪70年代末
Back in the late'70s,
蓖麻毒素曾被用来暗杀一名保加利亚记者
Ricin was used to assassinate a Bulgarian journalist.
克格勃间谍改造了一下伞尖
The KGB modified the tip of an umbrella
用它在那人腿上注入了那么一点
To inject a tiny pellet into the man's leg.
我说的一点  还没有针尖那么大
And we're talking about an amount not much bigger than the head of a pin.
-但能杀死他  -当然
- But it killed him? - Oh yes.
现在我们只要想出怎么给他下毒
Now we just need to figure out a delivery device,
然后  就没屠库这个人了
And then...no more Tuco.
最近怎样
How you doing?
我来的不是时候吗
Is this...This a bad time?
没事  进来吧
No, come on in.
抱歉  我该先打个电话的
I should've called first.I'm sorry.
有什么事吗
What can I do for you?
也许我们该...
Maybe we ought...
你想先坐下聊吗
You want to sit down first?
我不知道  汉克
I don't know, Hank.
得看你要聊的是不是玛丽的事
Depends on whether or not this is gonna be about Marie.
她让你来的吗
Did she send you?
不是的
Hell, no.
她都不怎么跟我讲话了
She's barely even talking to me.
所以我才来找你  好吗
That's why I'm here, okay?
为求自保
Self-preservation.
刻不容缓
Big time.
我知道你们姐妹俩时好时坏的
Look,I know you gals have your ups and downs.
-这点我知道  -姐妹俩
- I get it. - Gals...
我搅合进来是因为  我也有生理需要的嘛
And I need to get involved like I need a second hole in my ass.
看我的面子上  帮我个忙  给她回个电话吧
But if you could do me this huge favor and just return her phone calls.
我还不
I don't...
还不准备理她
Think I'm quite ready to do that yet.
你知道的  沟通  沟通万岁  对吧
You know, communication.Communication, right?
退一步海阔天空  拜托了
The back, the forth.Come on.
斯凯勒  看我的面子上  求你了
Sky, do this for me, please.
你可以冲她吼几句
You can yell at her.
就回个电话给她吧
Just call her back.
玛丽她入店行窃了  汉克
Marie is a shoplifter, Hank.
就是这样
That's right.
记得婴儿送礼会上她送的那个头饰
That "Baby Shower" she gave me at the shower?
那是她在圣扎迦利婴儿用品店偷来的
She stole it from Gertrude Zachary's.
我去退货的时候差点被抓起来
I almost got arrested when I went back to return it.
玛丽她倒好  她不肯承认
And Marie won't admit it.
更不肯道歉
She won't apologize.
如果我知道你会去退货的话  我就不会
If I thought you were gonna return it, I would have never..you know.
这些你早就知道了
You knew about this?
我们正在想办法
We're working on it.
我是说  她去找了个心理治疗师  戴夫
I mean, she's got this therapist, Dave.
-戴夫很在行的  -戴夫很在行
- I mean, Dave is really good. - Dave's good.
但这是个渐进的过程  斯凯勒
But it's an ongoing process, Sky,
我们该理解她
And we have gotta be understanding.
我是说  我们该  我们该
You know? I mean, we've gotta... You know. We've gotta...
帮帮她
Support the shit out of her.
-是吗  -是的
- Do we? - Yeah.
需要帮助的人是我
I need support.
是我
Me!
将近40岁了  意外怀孕
The almost 40-year-old pregnant woman,
挺着这么个大肚子
With the surprise baby on the way.
丈夫又得了肺癌
And the husband with the lung cancer
还整天不知所踪  鬼才知道他去哪了
Who disappears for hours on end,and I don't know where he goes,
反正他也不怎么跟我说话了
And he barely even speaks to me anymore.
还有个喜怒无常的儿子  跟他老爸一个德性
With the moody son who does the same thing.
存款账户早就透支了
And the overdrawn checking account.
家里的热水器烧不了热水  还总往下漏锈水
And the lukewarm water heater that leaks rusty-looking crap
储藏柜的底都快给它烂掉了
And is rotting out the floor of the utility closet
我们甚至连修理费都付不起了
And we can't even afford to fix it.
但是  我明白
But, oh, I see!
现在我该说的是  汉克  求你了
Now I'm supposed to go,"Hank, please.
我能做点什么好呢  怎么才能帮上忙
"What can I possibly do to further benefit
我那妹妹  虽然娇生惯养  偷窃成癖
"My spoiled, kleptomaniac bitch sister
但谁让她到哪都是大家关注的焦点呢
"Who somehow always manages to be the center of attention!
老天明鉴  她才是那个
"'Cause God knows she's the one
制造麻烦的人呢
"With the really important problems!"
要我帮你看看那个储藏柜吗
Want me to take a look at that utility closet?
这样就可以了吗
That's all it takes?
这样就可以了
That's all it takes.
那么  现在怎么办
So, now what?
现在  我们安排下次交易
Now, we arrange our next meet,
这次要找个公共场所  舒适又安全的地方
In a public place this time.Nice and safe.
装得若无其事的样子
Business as usual.
跟往常一样  卖给他4磅货
And, uh, after we sell him our usual four pounds,
然后  我们把这个拿出来
Then we'll pull this out.
还有件事  屠库
"By the way, Tuco,
这是我们研制出来的新配方
"The new meth formula we've been working on.
有没有兴趣一试
"Would you care to try it?"
好  那么  新货在哪里
Okay, well, what's new about it?
我是说  以防万一  他问起的话我们怎么说
I mean just in case he asks. What do we say?
我不知道  随便扯点什么
I don't know.Whatever you want.
就说抽了会爽到颠
It gets the user insanely high.
这又不需要什么销售技巧
I mean, how much salesmanship do we really need?
那变态逮到啥都会往鼻子里面吸的
That degenerate snorts anything he gets his hands on.
好吧  说辞我们也暂且不论
Okay, well, we'll just put a pin in that, then.
总之  在接下来的48小时内
Anyway, within the next 48 hours,
也许72小时
Maybe 72,
他会死得像自然死亡那样
It'll look like natural causes.
怎么死  心脏病那样吗
What, like a heart attack?
或者  禽流感什么的
Or the flu, maybe.
他的手下不会发现任何异常
His associates won't know any differently,
而我们也不会被怀疑
And we'll be in the clear.
只要屠库不先对我们下手
Not if Tuco kills us first.
别出声
Just keep it down.
汉克  有事吗
Hey, Hank. What's up?
老兄
Hey, buddy.
你回过家了吗
You been home yet?
还没  怎么了
No.Why?
我把事情搞砸了
'Cause I really screwed up.
赶在斯凯勒对你大发牢骚之前  我先跟你道歉
I apologize in advance for the earful you're gonna hear from Skyler.
我本意是想让她和玛丽合好如初
I'm just trying to get her and Marie talking again.
我大错特错了  我就不该卷进去的
Big mistake.I should have just kept out of it.
好的  没事
Yeah, well, okay.
我真是个大嘴巴
Me and my big mouth, I guess.
你也不是有意的  没问题的  别担心了
Well, that happens.It's no problem.No worries.
谢谢你  兄弟  我很感激
Well, thanks, man.I appreciate that.
真是的  这些女人哪
Jesus, the wives, huh?
汉克  很不巧
Hank, unfortunately,
-我真的得  -不好意思  我就不耽误你了
- I really... - Oh, yeah, man, don't let me keep you.
事实上  我也在忙呢
Actually, I'm at work, so...
对了  想开开眼戒吗
You wanna see something really freaky?
-我倒是想  只是  -说真的  沃尔特  这简直是
- Well, I would, but... - Seriously, Walt, this is...
我和格米就在这个凶案现场呢  你真该见识一下  等等
You gotta check out this crime scene me and Gomie are at. Just a second.
先别挂  照片马上就发过去了
Hang on, hang on.It should be coming through right now.
没你想象得那么糟吧
Guess it could be worse, huh?
说不定哪天我们也跟这俩家伙一样了
We could be having a day like these two.
两个本地帮派的冲头
A couple of local bulletheads.
估计是惹错人了
Guess they pissed off the wrong guy.
沃尔特  你在听吗
Walt, you there?
-我得拿着这个  -不行  这是我的枪  我需要它
- I'm taking this. - No! It's my gun! I need it!
不  你逃得远远的就不需要枪了
No, you don't!Not if you leave town.
快离开这儿
Get out of here
屠库既然杀了怪诞  下一个肯定会来找我们
Tuco killing Gonzo means he's coming after us next.
我得先回家  我有家人要顾
I've gotta get home. My family.
无翻译
小沃尔特去哪了
Where's Walter Junior?
估计是去路易斯家吃晚饭去了
Having dinner at Louis's house.Supposedly.
整整一天  我一个人守着这个空房子
All day, I've had the whole house to myself.
这次  你又去哪了
So where have you been this time?
沃尔特  过来跟我说说话好吗
Walt, will you come in here and talk to me please?
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
我认得这两个家伙
I recognize these two knobjobs.
他们是屠库·塞拉曼加这个变态的手下
Known associates of a psychotic piece of shit named Tuco Salamanca.
-估计他用不着他们俩了  -是的
- Guess he got tired of associating. - Yeah.
-介意我过去看看吗  -请便
- Do you mind if I get in there? - No, go ahead.
大块头的死亡时间要晚点
The big one smells fresher.
找到致命伤了吗
You guys find a death wound?
血倒是流了很多  但没看到弹孔
I see lots of blood,but no bullet holes.
照片都拍好了吗
You done taking pictures?
好的  把他放平了准备尸检吧
All right.Let's lay them out flat.
我还是给你们让个道吧
Let me get out of your way here, man.
见鬼
Oh, snap!
瑞奇  给验尸官留点能解剖的东西吧
Damn, Ricky. Leave something for the coroner.
这个太赞了
Oh, this is beautiful.
我们能上杰·雷诺的节目了[著名脱口秀主持人]
Hey, someone call Jay Leno.
我们碰上了世上最笨的罪犯
We've got the world's dumbest criminal.
这家伙不是被杀的  看看这里
This guy wasn't murdered.Look.
大块头是到这搬这家伙的尸体
Big Stuff, here,was moving this guy's body,
肯定是动到了上面那堆东西
When the stack must have shifted.
砸在他手臂上  把他钉在了这儿
Crushed his arm, pinned him here,
他是失血过多挂掉的
And he bled out!
老天有眼啊  我爱死它了
Poetic justice.Oh, I love it.
可不是嘛
Don't you just?
给我和这家伙来张合影
Get a photo of me with this guy, all right?
拍这个大胖墩  记得要把大胖墩一起拍进去
Old Stumpy, here. Make sure you get the stump in there.
沃尔特  跟我说说话吧  求你了
Walt,would you talk to me, please?
我不知该从何说起
I don't know where to begin.
你TM到这来干嘛
What the hell are you doing here?
上车
Get in.
开车
Let's go.